<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GeekOops on GeekOops - SysOps for Geekos</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in GeekOops on GeekOops - SysOps for Geekos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 15:16:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geekoops.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ansible collectd</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20220629-collectd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 15:16:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20220629-collectd/</guid><description>The geekoops-collectd role is an Ansible role to install and configure collectd on an openSUSE Leap server. The role contains many configuration parameter with which you can enable a large set of collectd plugins.
Currently the plugin supports pushing to an InfluxDB server or setting up a prometheus webserver for metrics scraping.
Most common plugins have been considered for the role, but the state is not yet complete. If you miss a certain plugin, feel free to create a pull request or report it as an issue.</description></item><item><title>Idea</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/idea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:49:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/idea/</guid><description>geekoops is a collection of generic devops and sysops recipes with a strong focus on the openSUSE distribution. The main idea is to provide tested and simple-to-use building blocks for system administrator and engineers to easily setup and maintain their systems.
I started this project during the SUSE Hackweek 20 based on a personal need for some generic and easy-to-use ansible roles. The project was born from the believe that many more people have the same need and building something publicly available might help the one or another person in fulfilling its daily job.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/contribute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:37:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/contribute/</guid><description>How can I contribute? GeekOops is an open community project, i.e. everyone is welcome to improve existing roles or submit new repositories that fit the general idea.
The project is managed on github. You can contribute by
Creating issues on individual roles Creating Pull Requests to improve existing roles Push a new repository Because the number of participants is still low we don&amp;rsquo;t have a hangout place yet but this might change over time.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: nginx</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210505-tutorial-nginx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 13:35:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210505-tutorial-nginx/</guid><description>Welcome to GeekOops! This post acts as a tutorial to start with the first role of this project: Installing and configuring a nginx webserver via the geekoops-nginx role.
Tutorial Let&amp;rsquo;s assume we want to roll this role out on our imaginary jellyfish server. We need to have root ssh access to jellyfish. Ansible also supports sudo, but this is not covered here. So first make sure you can do the following</description></item><item><title>Example: Webserver (nginx+php-fpm)</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-example-webserver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 10:49:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-example-webserver/</guid><description>In this post we are going to setup our example jellyfish host to run nginx and php-fpm. Checkout the provided jellyfish.yml playbook for a quickstart. This example playbook also configures a virtual host and creates a typical phpinfo.php file to test your setup.
This provides a solid example to setup your own webserver running nginx with php-fpm atop which you can later on run other php applications like nextcloud or MediaWiki.</description></item><item><title>Ansible NEXT server</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-next/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:54:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-next/</guid><description>The geekoops-next ansible role makes it easy to setup your own PXE boot server. It configures dnsmasq to run a DHCP and TFTP server, from which your PXE clients can boot from. You can turn the DNS functionality of dnsmasq off, so that it is possible to run this PXE server next to another DNS server on the same host.
This role also extracts a minimum syslinux installation into your tftp directory.</description></item><item><title>Ansible PureFTPd</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-pureftpd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:49:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-pureftpd/</guid><description>The geekoops-pureftpd role is a configurable ansible role for setting up a PureFTPd ftp server. I choose PureFTPd because it appears to be more secure than ProFTPd. In comparison to vsftp, one server program can run both IPv4 and IPv6.
This role works on openSUSE Leap.
Role Variables PureFTPd is a highly configurable ansible role. See the following list of possible variables, but you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need much of them.</description></item><item><title>Ansible php-fpm</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-php-fpm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:42:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-php-fpm/</guid><description>The geekoops-php-fpm role is intended as a standalone php-fpm deployment that works in conjunction with any webserver. I use it with nginx in production. In principle it should also work together with apache2, but that&amp;rsquo;s something currently untested.
This role works with openSUSE Leap and is intended to ship enough requirements for most web applications to run. I run it in conjunction with Mediawiki and Nextcloud.
Role Variables This ansible role comes with a large set of configuration parameters.</description></item><item><title>Ansible nginx</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-nginx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 09:27:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/posts/20210326-nginx/</guid><description>The geekoops-nginx role is a simple Ansible role to install and setup nginx on a openSUSE Leap server. This is the first role of the project and kept as simple as possible: It installs nginx and optionally opens the firewall ports.
Example --- # Example playbook for nginx on jellyfish - hosts: jellyfish user: root roles: - role: geekoops-nginx vars: setup_default_page: true default_page_hostname: &amp;#34;{{ansible_host}}&amp;#34; config_firewall: true firewall_zone: &amp;#34;public&amp;#34;</description></item></channel></rss>