<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on GeekOops - SysOps for Geekos</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on GeekOops - SysOps for Geekos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:49:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://geekoops.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Idea</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/idea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:49:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/idea/</guid><description>geekoops is a collection of generic devops and sysops recipes with a strong focus on the openSUSE distribution. The main idea is to provide tested and simple-to-use building blocks for system administrator and engineers to easily setup and maintain their systems.
I started this project during the SUSE Hackweek 20 based on a personal need for some generic and easy-to-use ansible roles. The project was born from the believe that many more people have the same need and building something publicly available might help the one or another person in fulfilling its daily job.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/contribute/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:37:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://geekoops.github.io/pages/contribute/</guid><description>How can I contribute? GeekOops is an open community project, i.e. everyone is welcome to improve existing roles or submit new repositories that fit the general idea.
The project is managed on github. You can contribute by
Creating issues on individual roles Creating Pull Requests to improve existing roles Push a new repository Because the number of participants is still low we don&amp;rsquo;t have a hangout place yet but this might change over time.</description></item></channel></rss>